原创翻译  双语字幕
最新连载海外影视剧下载
请登陆 www.YYeTs.com
仅供交流学习  禁止商用盈利
翻译     千只鹤飞过波千鸟  tong大梨  AlgerDestiny
翻译     五天  二糯米  不见咖啡  VioletCheng
校对     屯栗子
时间轴     西·查
后期     渔夫
总监     屯栗子
辛普森一家
第三十一季  第十二集
晚上好  霍雷肖先生
Guten Abend, Herr Horatio.
把剩下的给我
Gib mir die Karte.
田镇
春田镇
春田镇对吧
Springfield, eh?
那就是我要去的寻宝之地
Then that's where I'm going treasure hunting.
你是说我们要去的寻宝之地
You mean we're going treasure hunting.
我们会在这周内找到沉船
We'll find that sunken ship within the week.
Grid 274 by 319.
四十年后
深度60米  声呐探测
Depth 60 meters. Sounding.
无果
Nothing.
继续下一个读数
Proceed to next reading.
Grid 274 by 320.
深度60米  声呐探测
Depth 60 meters. Sounding.
无果
Nothing.
船长  长范围多普勒雷达显示
Captain, the long-range Doppler shows a squall
暴风正从东北方过来
coming out of the nor'east.
我们最好掉头回去等风暴过去
We'd best head back to wait it out.
我猜猜  你今天没寻到宝
Let me guess, you didn't find any treasure today.
你跟医生说增加药量的事了吗
Did you talk to the doctor about going up on your dose?
风暴搅乱了海底
The storm stirred up the seafloor.
我们必须从断脊的南面重新探测
We'll have to resound everything south of the break.
坐标  274 6
Grid 274 by 6.
深度30米  声呐探测
Depth 30 meters. Sounding.
无果
Nothing.
我做了烤肉当晚饭
I made us a roast for dinner,
然后丢掉了
then threw it away.
很抱歉我一直没能给你一儿半女
I'm sorry I never gave you any children.
Grid 291 by 502.
深度70米  声呐探测
Depth 70 meters. Sounding.
第二声回响
A second ping.
A second ping!
我等了大半辈子就为了说这句
I've waited half a lifetime to say this.
潜水员们  上装备
Divers, gear up!
我们找到了
We found it.
我们终于找到了伙计们
We finally found it, boys!
我没浪费这一生
I didn't waste my life!
市长
你是来惊叹咱的战利品的吧
I see you've come to admire our plunder.
其实这些战利品属于这个小镇
technically that plunder belongs to the town.
它是在春田镇政府管辖范围内被发现的
It was discovered in Springfield city limits.
不  我们在非建制海域内发现了金子
No, we found the gold in unincorporated waters!
这些发现属于我们
The survey says it's ours!
抱歉  春田镇重新规划了界限
Sorry, but the town redrew the boundaries...
春田镇
就在昨天
yesterday.
但我们秘密工作了四十年
But we worked in secret for 40 years.
我假装成一个浅薄单调的小角色
I pretended to be a flimsy, one-note character.
你怎么知道的
How did you know?
我本该是你的宝贝
I should have been your treasure.
春田镇政府
今晚会议主题
如何享受我们的财宝
各位  春田镇发掘了一批财宝
All right, people. This town's got doubloons.
谁有好主意
Who's got ideas?
如果我没听到好主意  我们就再建一座体育场
If I don't hear anything good, we're building another stadium,
没有参赛队会来
and no team will come here.
不如建一座新钟楼  每一小时
How about a new town clock where, every hour,
耶稣都在原谅魔鬼
Jesus forgives the Devil?
建一家新动物园  多放点有意思的动物
A new zoo with more attractive animals.
承诺给我们的死亡小组呢
What about those death panels we were promised?
政治术语
起源于2009年有关联邦医疗保健立法的辩论
不知道想说什么  先喊两嗓子
Shouting out something before I know what I'm gonna say.
没有珍珠果酱乐队的摇滚名人堂
Rock & Roll Hall of Fame with no Pearl Jam!
抱歉  我有个主意
Excuse me. I have an idea.
马姬  你看看安排
Now, Marge, if you'll check your program,
唠叨者反对在最后一项
nagging objections are at the end.
会议安排
1)宣布宝藏
2)有趣的主意
3)操纵投票
4)唠叨者反对
看看这个世界
Look at the world.
孩子们的未来充满挑战与未知
Our children's future is challenging and uncertain.
这笔天降之财是我们最后的最佳的机会
This windfall is our last, best hope
赋予孩子们面向未来时可能需要的工具
to give our kids the tools they'll need to face that future.
为了成功  我们的孩子们必须要接受教育
To succeed, our kids must have an education
基于科学  技术
based on science, technology,
工程  还有数学
engineering and math.
简称科技工数
STEM.
如果觉得马姬的主意很无聊
All who find Marge's idea tiresome,
打一个夸张讽刺的呵欠
let out an exaggerated, sarcastic yawn.
好吧  好吧  我请了一个人
Okay, okay. I brought someone
你们肯定愿意听他说"科技工数"教育
you will listen to about STEM education.
哥伦比亚唱片艺术家约翰·传奇
Columbia recording artist John Legend.
*科技工数  科学  技术  工程  数学*
*STEM, science, tech, engineering and math*
*不仅仅是计算机课的时髦说法*
*More than a trendy way to say computer class*
*科技工数  不仅为了傻子呆子和书呆子*
*STEM, it's not just for dorks, dweebs and nerds*
*能把你们的废物孩子变成扎克·伯格*
*It'll turn all your dumb kids to Zuckerbergs*
*科技工数  因为这未来用代码书写*
*STEM, 'cause the future is written in code*
*做个应用  上市就能赚大钱*
*Make an app, get big cash from an IPO*
*科技工数*
*STEM*
*Oh, STEM*
谁能拒绝丝滑的慢爵士
Who could say no to a silky slow jam
歌唱学习科学技术的重要性
about the importance of technology-based learning?
我永远不会有孩子  因为我的蛋被科学虐惨了
I'll never have kids because my nards were cooked by science.
但是如果我能有孩子  我希望他们能学习
But if I could, I'd want 'em to learn
导致他们不能存在的科学
about the science of why they don't exist.
我想感谢约翰·传奇...的太太
I'd just like to thank John Legend...'s wife
克莉茜·泰根  带他来到现场
Chrissy Teigen for bringing him here today.
结果发现  她最爱的
Turns out, there's nothing she loves more
就是帮图享粉丝的忙
than doing personal favors for her Instagram followers.
马姬  我小孩脸上沾着番茄酱的照片
Well, Marge, you did call the picture I posted
你都评论了"可可爱爱"
of my kids with ketchup on their faces "adorbs."
的确  灰常可可爱爱
It was. It was totes adorbs.
宝贝  我们该走了
Baby, we got to get going.
要赶不上我们夫妇款香水的发布会了
We're gonna be late for the launch party for our couples' perfume.
我在和我的网友线下聊天
I'm talking to my online friend IRL.
去给孩子的平板电脑充电
Go charge the kids' iPads.
来吧  春田镇
Come on, Springfield!
给你们的孩子建立明日校园
Build your children the school of tomorrow.
我做到了
I did it.
我给了孩子们未来的希望
I gave our kids hope for the future.
有没有歌写的是
You have any songs about
我能不履行评审团义务
how I should be allowed to skip jury duty?
*列入评审名单算什么公正*
*How is it justice to impanel a man*
*在疯狂三月的日子里*
*During March Madness?*
春田镇科技工数学院
领导  如果你被迫退休会去做什么
What are you gonna do with your forced retirement, sir?
我对本地的一家跳伞俱乐部感兴趣
I'm intrigued by a local skydiving club
他们需要有人在办公室接电话
who needs someone to sit in the office and answer phones.
谁在乎呢
Yeah, well, who cares?
我会去俄亥俄河坐船[猎艳]
I'll be taking an Ohio River cruise.
那里有好多寡妇
Lot of widows on the Good River.
好多寡妇
Lot of widows.
新学校的气味
New school smell.
无纸化教室  个人平板电脑
Paperless classrooms, personal tablets,
还有不能乱塞东西的储物柜
and uncrammable lockers.
这太尴尬了
Man, this is embarrassing.
一家二十一世纪的学校
巴仔·辛普森
Bart Simpson.
欢迎  我叫赞恩·弗朗  是这所学校的CEO
Welcome. I'm Zane Furlong, this school's CEO:
合作教育导师
Collaborative Educational Outreacher.
史金纳二代  我要打断你一下
I'm gonna stop you right there, Skinner 2.0.
我不管你怎么包装
It doesn't matter how you dress it up.
所有学校都是儿童监狱
All schools are kid prisons.
我要让你在这里独处
Well, I'm putting you in solitary,
你能在这里通过射击流星来学习几何学
where you'll learn geometry by shooting meteors.
到达一定阶段
Shoot enough,
你会解锁个性化的皮肤
and you'll unlock customizable skins.
皮肤
Skins?
男孩的打扮游戏
That's how boys play dress-up.
丽莎·辛普森
Lisa Simpson.
我们的教育标准已经确定
Our educational metric has identified you
你是发散式前途光明的同化者
as a divergent multipathway assimilator.
你是说我能进天才班
You mean, I'm in a gifted class?
我们不喜欢这种说法
Ooh, we don't like that term.
每个人都有天赋
Everyone is gifted.
我坚信
I firmly believe that.
现在上楼去
Now go upstairs to the...
天才班
gifted class.
我终于被别人发掘出来了
Finally, I feel seen.
这是我第一次
And for the first time, I'll be accepted by my peers
被同龄人所接纳
with open arms.
我到家了
I'm home.
好了  天才班的同学们
Okay, gifted class.
休息结束了
Recess is over.
现如今  这所学校非常先进
Now, this school is so advanced
算法
以至于到处都能看到算法的存在
that every aspect of it is run by an algorithm.
关于算法谁能给我举个例子
Who can give me an example of an algorithm?
就像是你在网上买了一个垃圾桶
Like when you buy a new garbage can online
往后余生都能看到垃圾桶的广告
and the rest of your life, you see ads for garbage cans.
就像你看一些YouTube上的近景魔术视频之后
Or like when you watch a bunch of close-up magic videos on YouTube
就会看到自杀求助热线的广告
and get ads for a suicide hotline.
没错
Exactly.
因为你们都喜欢这个课程
And because you liked this lesson,
算法会推测出你可能喜欢
the algorithm thinks you might also enjoy...
神经网络入门  C语言编程  谋杀之谜
克莉茜&传奇香水
你在我创立的新学校第一天感觉怎么样
How was your first day at the new STEM school I founded?
太好了  我们学习了科学
It was amazing. We did science,
然后我们学习了计算机科学
then we did computer science,
后来我们学习了认知计算机科学
and then we did cognitive computer science.
真想不到  丽莎喜欢学校
Oh, what a surprise. Lisa likes school.
你呢儿子  今天又因为什么被停学了
All right, boy. What did you get suspended for today?
没
Nothing.
我也喜欢这学校
I like this school, too.
不再由老师打分
Instead of teachers giving us letter grades,
算法会评判你得了几颗星
an algorithm gives us stars.
学校算法
巴仔·辛普森
教育现在就是场游戏  我玩的还不错
Education is a game now, and I'm great at it.
看看我解锁了的皮肤
Look at all these skins I've already unlocked.
瞧瞧
Oh, that guy.
奈斯
Noice.
我甚至解锁了"解锁皮肤"勋章
I even unlocked the "Skin Unlocking" badge.
会堂
职业日
辛普森先生  告诉大家你是做什么的
Tell us, what do you do, Mr. Simpson?
职业日
我在核电站
Ah, yes. I monitor the core temperature
监控核心温度
at the nuclear power plant.
如果指示灯变红
If it gets into the red,
我首先会告诉家人
I tell my family first so they can leave town
以便在街道变拥挤前离开镇子
before the streets get too crowded.
完美的例子
Now, this is a great example...
这类工作很快就会消失
...of the kind of job that will soon cease to exist.
啥玩意
What the words now?
辛普森先生的日常工作
Mr. Simpson's daily tasks
机器人会更高效完成
can be more efficiently performed by robots.
预计此类工作十八个月内会消失
My guess is, his job will be obsolete in 18 months.
他们呢  他们的职业还有多久
What about them? How much time do their careers have?
-我是图书馆员  -五年
- I'm a librarian. - Five years.
我刚买了纽约市出租车牌照
I just bought a New York City taxi medallion.
五年前就没了
Five years ago.
我在一家大麻配送公司做媒体
I do social media for a cannabis delivery company.
你没事
You'll be fine.
但其他工作很快会被
But all these other jobs will soon be made obsolete
自动化取代
by automation.
天呐  机器人时代来了
Oh, no. The robots are coming!
我得去提醒大家
I've got to warn everyone!
这些蠢孩子
Stupid kids!
会堂
我所有科目都是五星
I'm getting five stars in all my classes.
我终于解锁了鬓角脏辫
I finally unlocked dreadlock sideburns.
某人的用户名上榜了哟
Someone's user name is moving up the leaderboard.
星榜
1二次方霍
2我是肖娜
3巴仔恶魔
4拉尔夫
5鸡冻小婊砸
现在下楼
Now get back downstairs
准备明天的工作吧
to prepare for the jobs of tomorrow.
真是一场降维打击啊
It's a race to the bottom!
学校算法
巴仔  我从没见过你这么投入学习
Bart, I've never seen you so engaged in learning.
棒极了  看看我们能在镇上收集
It's awesome. We're seeing how many e-scooters
多少辆电动车
we can collect around town,
充电后再送回去
charge, then get back on the streets.
明白了  你在学习逻辑和空间推理
Oh, I see. You're learning logic and spatial reasoning.
我只知道一分钟内收集不够十辆电动车
All I know is, if I don't get ten scooters in under a minute,
就解锁不了收集大师勋章
I won't unlock the Master Collector badge.
学校算法
拿到了  学习太棒了
Got it! Learning rules!
收藏大师
交易经济学
您一定是在教孩子们营养知识
Oh, you must be teaching the kids about nutrition
以及控制预算  对吗
and staying within a budget, right?
不  我们在教他们帮懒惰富人购物
No. We're teaching them to buy groceries for lazy rich people.
这个牛油果两天后就到完美熟度了
This avocado will be perfectly ripe in two days.
不知道尝起来会是什么味道
I wonder what they taste like.
开优步
Uber-driving.
送外卖
Grubhub'ing.
开来福车
Lyft-driving?
lyft“来福车”是美国第二大打车公司
这些才不是未来职业
These aren't jobs of the future.
这些都只是兼职副业
These are side hustles!
大伙们
Guys, guys.
机器人要来了  机器人要来了
The robots are coming. The robots are coming!
这里
Robots here?
恐怕没有那么前沿
Uh, this place ain't exactly forward-thinking.
我们是美国最后一批
Yeah. We're one of America's
还在用煤电的核工厂
last coal-powered nuclear plants.
你们就把头埋进三明治里假装看不见吧
Yeah? Well, you can all bury your heads in the sandwiches,
可我知道  机器人要来取代我们了
but I know the robots are coming to replace us!
冷静  侯默
Calm down, Homer.
从我们的新汽水机里倒杯饮料喝
Here, have a drink from the new soda machine we got.
汽水
巴斯可乐
想喝就喝
机器已经入侵了
The machines are already here,
等它们取得统治  你想象不到
and when they take over, you can't imagine
未来会多么惨淡
how bleak the future will be.
我选择相信好日子就要来了
I choose to believe our best days are ahead of us.
生活愉快
它在命令我们
It's giving us orders.
星火已经在燎原了
The revolution has begun.
我认得那个表情
I know that look.
她又要搅乱好事了
She's gonna Lisa-up a good thing.
同学们  注意了
Attention, students!
这间学校才不是在教你们怎么开发软件
This school isn't training you to program apps.
它在训练你们服从软件
It's training you to obey apps!
你们长大以后  基本工资都无法保障
When you're grown up, you'll be lucky to make minimum wage!
那也有很多钱
Which is a lot of money!
就像每个小时都给你零花钱一样
That's like getting your allowance every hour.
什么  不  别
Wha...? No, no.
你们和天才班的学生一样都值得成功机会
You deserve the same chance to succeed as the gifted class.
那意味着为真正的职业做准备
That means preparing for real careers,
而不是打零工
not gig economy gigs.
打零工超级好  DJ都打零工[gigs也有现场表演的意思]
Gigs are awesome! DJs play gigs!
DJ万岁
DJs!
这和打碟没有半毛钱关系
This has nothing to do with deejaying!
黎曼猜想
至少他们还有美术课
At least they are learning art.
因果报应  欢迎小费  提前支付  改变有益
小费罐
Tip jars?!
受够了  我得整治这个学校
That's it. I got to fix this school.
校内算法
别给学校捣乱了
Stop messing with the school.
我好不容易填满了足够的虚拟小便瓶
I finally filled up enough virtual pee bottles
才解锁了亚马逊仓库管理专家徽章
to unlock the Amazon Warehouse Whizzer badge.
仓库管理专家
巴仔·辛普森
巴仔  我要重写算法
Bart, I need to rewrite the algorithm.
然后学校会给所有学生教真正的科技工数
Then the school will teach every kid real STEM.
我是为了你好
I am doing this for you.
是吗  我也是为了我好
Yeah? Well, I'm doing this for me.
电子扫把
电子码尺
为了平等教育
Education for all!
大部分人只配跑腿
Side hustles for most!
孩子们  怎么回事
Kids, what's wrong?
你们体内的追踪器显示你们情绪有波动
Your tracking implants showed heightened emotions.
-哪里的追踪器  -老师  老师
- Tracking what? - Teacher, teacher,
我妹妹想要搞垮
my sister's gonna ruin the only school
我唯一喜欢过的学校
I've ever liked in my whole life!
只有一小部分学生
It's just not fair that only a small group of kids
能得到高等教育太不公平了
are getting an advanced education!
这不正是天才班存在的意义吗
Well, isn't that the point of a gifted class?
丽莎  算法的目的
Lisa, the algorithm's purpose
就是让孩子们为将来的工作做好准备
is to prepare kids for the jobs of tomorrow.
但算法只教孩子们如何完成当天的跑腿任务
But it's just teaching them to be the task rabbits of today.
没人知道明天的工作内容是什么
Nobody knows what the jobs of tomorrow are gonna be.
我确定算法知道
Well, I'm sure the algorithm does.
来让我问问它
Here, I'll ask it.
等等  这不可能
Wait, wait, this can't be.
只有一项工作内容
There's only one.
这下我们完蛋了
We are so screwed.
春田核电站
一杯香草青柠口味巴斯可乐
One Buzz Cola with vanilla and lime.
来一杯无糖巴斯可乐
Diet Buzz for me.
香草青柠口味的
With vanilla and lime.
我的天  又来
Aw, geez. This again?
我们有着积极向上的生活方式
Yeah, we have an active lifestyle,
包括每天喝汽水
and part of that is drinking soda all day.
如果你们这么爱喝的话
If it's refreshments you want,
为什么不让人类给你们倒汽水
why not let a man pour your soda!
一名人类男性
A human man.
一直以来我们都在放任
For too long we have done nothing
任由机器替代我们的工作  帮我们洗碗
as machines have taken over, washing our dishes,
给我们注射胰岛素  现在又是这个
pumping our insulin, and now this!
人类可以比任何专门为了倒汽水
Man can pour soda better than any machine
而订制的机器做得更好  我会证明的
made specially for that purpose, and I will prove it!
今天是机械崛起结束的日子
Today the robot uprising ends.
今天是人类的独立日
Today is our Independence Day!
约翰·侯默的歌谣
*侯默倒了许多杯汽水*
*Well, Homer pulled a lot of sodas*
*因为他憎恨汽水机*
*Because he hated that machine*
*他糊涂啦  以为机器会抢了他的饭碗*
*He got confused, thought it was gonna take his job*
*所以侯默成了倒水人  老天老天*
*So Homer was a soda-pouring man, Lord, Lord*
*侯默成了倒水人*
*Oh, Homer was a soda-pouring man*
*他没能证明自己的观点*
*He did not make his point
*而且他的汽水又不冰又没气*
*And his sodas were warm and flat*
*所以侯默成了倒水人  老天老天*
*So Homer was a soda-pouring man, Lord, Lord*
*倒汽水可不是什么正经事*
*Soda-pouring's not a real thing*
*根本不是*
*No, sir*
或许侯默倒汽水要慢一些
Homer might have been slower,
但他倒的汽水富有人类情感
but his pours had a human touch.
脸上挂着微笑  饱含兄弟情谊
Always delivered with a smile and a sense of brotherhood.
讲的真好
Yeah! All right!
但他死了  是机器赢了
But he died. So machine wins!
不  等一下  他喝了太多汽水
No, no, wait. His pulse was beating so fast
脉搏跳动得太快了都模糊了
from all the soda he drank that it was a blur.
也许终有一天
Perhaps one day machines will be better
机器会比人类更擅长倒汽水  但绝不是今天
at pouring soda than man, but not today!
我们的工作保住了
Our jobs are safe!
春田镇科技工数学院
听着
Listen up.
这些呆子们发现了一些吓人的事
These nerds have found out something terrifying.
这所学校本应为你们将来的
This school was supposed to prepare you
职业发展做准备
for the jobs of the future.
但在将来  我们在这所学的工作
But in the future, all the jobs we've learned here
都将由机器人完成
will be done by robots.
给人类做的工作只有...
The only job left for humans will be...
照顾老人
Elder care!
这份工作连机器人都不愿做
The one job even robots won't do.
那STEM呢
What about STEM?
这才是它真正的含义
Here's what it really stands for.
擦身浴
上厕所
老年人
按摩
-不  -不可能
- No! - No, it can't be!
分享装三明治
冲向门口[外卖]
冲向手术室救护车
我可不想长大后帮人擦屁股
I don't want to be an adult butt wiper.
大家都不该看到裸体的老年人
No one should see old people naked!
除非那是你的癖好
Unless that's your kink.
我们让这算法见识一下我们真正的想法吧
Let's show this algorithm what we really think of it--
用我们这代人最强有力的手段
with our generation's most powerful tool:
用户评分
user ratings.
用户评分过低
User rating dangerously low.
一星
One star.
自尊协议失灵
Self-esteem protocol failing.
情感矩阵旋转中...
Emotion matrix spiraling...
旋转中
spiraling.
零星
Zero stars.
无法脱离虚拟层
Can't get out of virtual bed.
启动自毁程序
Initiating self-destruct sequence.
自毁
Self-destruct.
我得回去  我的皮肤还在里面
I have to go back! My skins are in there!
不  它们已经消失了
No! They're already gone!
迷彩帽圣诞老人  不
Camo-hat Santa! No!
我想孩子们得回去以前的学校了
I guess the children will have to go back to the old school.
是啊  我不知道还有没有可能了
Yes, well, I don't know that that's possible anymore.
摇滚名人堂
不要珍珠果酱乐队
我的学校
My school.
我思想超前的学校
My forward-thinking school.
好了  好了  你会想出别的主意的
There, there. You'll suggest other schools.
你真这么觉得吗
You really think so?
我只是随口说说
I'm just saying things.
再见了  天才班
Goodbye, gifted class.
是啊  不过我们不用照顾老人了
Yeah, but we escaped having to take care of old people.
不  那还是唯一会存在的工作
No, that's still the only job that's going to exist.
只是我们不会知道要怎么做了
Now we just won't know how to do it.
快递伙计[外卖]
你的辣翅到了
I've got your hot wings.
垃圾鸡翅
芹菜杆也在里面吗
Did you include celery sticks?
是的  先生
Yes, sir.
无小费
你觉得未来的工作会是什么样的
What do you really think the jobs of the future will be?
科技的发展日新月异
Well, technology is changing so fast,
谁知道它会把我们带到何处呢
who knows where it will finally take us?
来点巴斯可乐
Buzz Cola.
你要无糖的还是正常的
You want diet or regular?
正常的  人渣
Regular, human scum.
加上香草和青柠
With vanilla and lime.
算法可没预测这个
The algorithm never predicted this.
算法是什么
What's an algorithm?